Akshaya Aishwarya K B 🕡 Featured

Programmer Analyst seeking roles in Software Development, Software Design, Change Management, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, SQL Server, Apache Tomcat, Java 8, Spring boot, J-unit, Pro*C, PLSQL, Shell script, Oracle, Putty, Eclipse, Jetty, JIRA, Git, C, C++



Current Designation: Programmer Analyst Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Cognizant Technology Solutions India Ltd Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Chennai Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Chennai

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: SQL Server, Apache Tomcat, Oracle, Putty, Eclipse, Jetty, JIRA, Git, C, C++, Core Java, Spring Boot, PLSQL, Software

Developer, SQL, Java

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

1 year and four months experience in software development using C, Pro*C,SHELL SCRIPT,SQL in UNIX environment. Have experience in VISA and MASTER testing tool.

Good knowledge in C++ development in Fedora environment using QT creator.

Good knowledge in SQL and PL/SQL development and in UNIX commands

Good understanding of Switch of Citibank.

Good understanding of payment Gateway transaction model of Amazon.

Good knowledge of payment card industry.

Always motivated to take independent responsibility as well as ability to continue and be a productive team member.

Have one year experience in software developing using C++,SQL in UNIX environment.

To serve an organization that provides me the opportunity to prove and improve my skill, knowledge and potential, to nurture my professional growth in-line with the organizational objective.

Work Experience

Cognizant Technology Solutions India Ltd as Programmer Analyst

Nov 2019 to Till Date

Cognizant Technologies Solutions as Programmer Analyst Nov 2019 to Nov 2019

1. Title - Scheduler 2.0 April 2019 -August 2020

Client : Walmart Corp Role : Developer (JAVA)

Skill Set: Rest web sersvices using spring boot framework

Project Details:

Worked in Scheduler 2.0 integration project. Scheduler, a third party system which sends a JSON payload including history of all appointments to GLS classic. We created a new java layer module which hold the responsibility of carrying out operations as per business requirements like appointment level validations, appointment processing with DB insertions, updations and deletions with respect to event type, List of Purchase orders with po level validations, po level processing with DB insertions and updations and deletions with respect to events provided. This project is applicable for International, USG and FSC market.

· Roles and Responsibilities:

- Responsible for coding using Java 8 tech stack.
- * Module development as per requirements in Java using spring boot framework.
- * Complete unit testing and integration of the software.
- * Performed End-to-End Unit test for Modules delivery.
- * We follow agile Methodology, by having regular scrums.
- Explanations of previous and ongoing batch requirements and functionality.
- 2. Title E gift card December 2019 March 2020

Role: Developer (JAVA)

Skill Set: Core Java, Junit, SQL, Apache camel

Project Details: Worked in ESM posting, e-gift card project. Done the project as per business requirements.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- * Been a part of design and Requirement analysis.
- * Responsible for coding using java, apache camel and sql.
- * Delivered in time.
- 3. Junit November, 2019 May, 2020

Skill Set :Core Java, Junit, SQL

Project Details:

I have written many junit test cases almost for all repos in gls.

Worked in Ei-allocation and Ei-order event project.

- * Roles and Responsibilities:
- o Been a part of design and Requirement analysis.
- Completed coding and testing as expected.

Crown Solutions as Programmer Analyst

Jul 2019 to Nov 2019

Skill Set :Core Java, Junit, SQL Client : CTS, Walmart

Project Details:

I have written many junit test cases almost for all repos in gls.

Worked in Ei-allocation and Ei-order event project.

- * Roles and Responsibilities:
- Been a part of design and Requirement analysis.
- o Completed coding and testing as expected

Yalamanchili Software Exports as Junior Software Developer

Jul 2017 to Oct 2018

Client: CITI Bank Role: Developer, Tester

Skill Set: UNIX, SQL, PL/SQL, C, PRO*C

Responsible for

- ? Enhance the coding part as per the business requirement.
- ? Creating or enhance the stored procedure as per the business requirement.
- ? For monitoring the Citibank Switch Flow.
- ? To prepare test cases for testing process to check the enhancement meets the business requirement.
- ? Preparing a Quality Analysis Document , analyzing test results, whether that?s meets the business requirements for QA Release.
- ? Involved in impacts analysis for integration of Switch.
- ? Providing support for fixing production issue and for live movement code issue.
- ? Title : Issuing Transaction Report May 2018 ? June, 2018

Environment : C, Pro*C, UNIX OSF1 Alpha Version, PLSQL Database : Oracle11g

Role: Developer, Tester

Project name: Payment Gateway

Project description: To take the count of issuing transactions of VISA, MASTER organizations

Responsibilities : For issuing transactions of VISA and MASTER organizations, extract the chip, PG and recurring details from the table with ISO DUMP and provide a daily and monthly approved and declined transaction counts through excel . Also, done a testing to check whether those changes are reflected in the business requirement.

? Title: Switch Logmonitor April 2018

Environment : Shell Script, UNIX OSF1 Alpha Version

Role: Developer, Tester Project name: Switch

Project description: As per the business requirement monitoring the logs in all servers in Citibank.

Responsibilities : Done a shell scripting for the servers in switch side to check the logs in each server node's running

properly and also done a testing to check whether those changes are reflected in the business requirement.

? Title: Switch File Transfer Feburary 2018 ? March 2018

Environment : Shell script, UNIX OSF1 Alpha Version

Role : Developer , Tester Project name : Switch

Project description: To transfer files from one server to another server in switch.

Responsibilities : Done a shell scripting to do SCP and also done a testing to check those changes are reflected in the

business requirement.

? Title: ATM File Transfer January 2018

Environment : Shell script, UNIX OSF1 Alpha Version

Role : Developer and Tester Project name : Switch

Project Description: To copy, backup the files, transfer the files

Responsibilities : Done a shell scripting to do transferring the files, copy, backup , nullify, checksum calculation of ATM

files and also done a testing to check whether those changes are reflected in the business requirement.

? Title : EMV Rupay - NFS November, 2017 ? December, 2017

Environment : C, Pro*C, UNIX OSF1 Alpha Version, PLSQL Database : Oracle11g

Role : Developer , Tester Project name : Switch

Project description: Passing the bins from the generated reports

Responsibilities : Creating the new database object for storing the EMV BIN?s which has been shared by NPCI on

regular basis and done a testing to check whether those changes are reflected in the business requirement.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from HINDUSTHAN COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING AND TECHNOLOGY, COIMBATORE in 2017

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
PRO C,PLSQL, SQL			
c, unix commands			
Windows XP/8/8.1, UNIX			
SQL Server, Oracle 9i			
VTS, MASTER			
putty, Winscp			
Ms-office 2000/2003			
Eclipse, JIRA, GIT, Putty,SOAP UI			
Linux Shell Scripting , Java,Junit			
CORE JAVA		2017	2 Year(s) 6 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				

Tamil

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time